Finding Aid for George Vargas papers, 1973-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Papers, Publications, and Non-conference Lectures
  - Ballet Folklórico Greeting Card project, Flint, Michigan 1989 (Box 3)
  - Bridging Cultures: Latino Art in the US and the Latin-American Spirit: Where do we go from here?, University of Michigan March 22, 1990 (Box 3)
    (Vargas slide show and panel presentation)
  - Chicano Art, El Paso Museum of Art lecture September 24, 1992 (Box 3)
    (Vargas lecture)
  - Chicano Art, SYEP lecture, University of Texas at El Paso August 5, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Circles / Circulos: A Mural by George Vargas 1989 (Box 3)
    (narrative and sketches)
  - City Spirit 2001 (Box 3)
    (article by Vargas on Vargas mural, see also "Art Show Posters, etc." under "Original Artwork")
  - Contemporary Latino Art, Oakland University, Rochester, Michigan February 23, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Contemporary Latino Art in Michigan, University of Michigan January 15, 1990 (Box 3)
    (Vargas lecture during celebration of Martin Luther King Jr. Day)
  - Crossroads Presentation Materials: Hispanics in Higher Education, Oakland University, Rochester, Michigan October 12, 1989 (Box 3)
    (Vargas with Patricia Montenegro, Spanish Dept.)
  - Cultural Democracy, Detroit Institute of Arts April 22, 1989 (Box 3)
    (Vargas panel discussion)
  - Diego Rivera April 3, 1985 (Box 3)
    (Vargas slide lecture)
  - Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo in Detroit
    (Vargas slide lectures)
    - Art Institute of Chicago January 7, 1991 (Box 3)
    - University of Texas at El Paso February 18, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Four Spanish Painters: Goya, Picasso, Dali, Varo: Their Links and Influences in World Art, International Institute of Flint, Michigan March 21, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Latino Art in Michigan, Eastern Michigan University September 1985 (Box 3)
  - Mural Lecture, University of Texas at El Paso June 15, 1992 (Box 3)
    (Vargas Lecture)
  - Photographic Images Across the Borders, El Paso Art Museum September 1993 (Box 3)
    (Vargas lecture on Mexican photography)
  - Raza Art and Media Collective Journal January 1976-June 1977 (Box 3)
    (includes Vargas contributions and artwork, see also "Original Artwork" for Vol. 2 No. 1 June 1977 galley proofs)
  - Rivera and Kahlo, Centennial Museum, University of Texas at El Paso May 18, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Untitled Vargas lecture, Latino and Hispanic Art, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Voces Del Norte II, publication by Michigan State University 1979 (Box 3)
    (Vargas contribution)
- Original Artwork
  The sixth and final series, Original Artwork, contains 2-D artwork by Vargas in a variety of sizes and mediums, and a few items as listed that relate to other materials in the collection. Among the non-Vargas artwork are the Raza Art and Media Collective Journal galley proofs, the Labyrinth of the Americas poster which has text by Vargas, two posters by Jon Onye Lockard, and the Art Show Posters, etc. which correspond with organizations, conferences, and exhibitions in the rest of the collection. The original artwork series is distributed between Box 3, Box 4, three UAl folders, and two tubes.
  - Vargas artwork (Box 3)
    (includes photographs)
  - Sketchbooks (Box 4)
  - Raza Art and Media Collective Journal galley proofs 1977 (Box 4)
    (see also "Raza Art and Media Collective" under "Papers, publications, and non-conference lectures")
  - Art Show Posters, etc. (Box 4)
  - Various artwork (Box 4)
  - Labyrinth of the Americas poster 2001 (Folder UAl 1)
    (text by Vargas)
  - Various artwork (Folder UAl 1)
    (medium size)
  - Various artwork (Folder UAl 2)
  - "Visions of Destiny" poster by Jon Onye Lockard (Folder UAl 3)
  - Various artwork (Folder UAl 3)
    (large size)
  - 2 pieces of rolled artwork (Tube 1)
  - 3 pieces of rolled artwork, each depicting a working man (Tube 2)
  - By Jon Onye Lockard March 1978 (Folder UAl 1)
    (see also "Lockard" under "Artists")